# Virginia L. Abernathy

187 Hornbeam Dr., Groton, CT 06340 732.986.6585

v\_abernathy@hotmail.com

# **Qualifications Summary:**

I am an energetic, highly motivated team player that fosters excellence and exhibits high standards while achieving extraordinary results. With many years of professional experience, I have benefited with increasing responsibilities in leadership, management, supervising, problem solving, and career development. I am focused on improving and learning techniques that enhance my professional experience.

## **Professional Experience:**

December 27, 2011 – February 10, 2012

Sarazin General Contractors, Inc.

Bookkeeper

Temporary position through Accountemps.

August 15, 2011 – October 27, 2011

Ocean House, Watch Hill, RI

#### **Staff Accountant**

- Processed weekly payroll through Paychex (300+) and created the General Ledger entries for accounting system.
- Reconciled monthly prepaid accrual spreadsheet and vacation accrual spreadsheet to GL.
- Assisted with monthly bank reconciliations.
- Prepared various General Ledger entries and reconciled accounts.

December 2, 2010 – July 15, 2011

Townsend & Associates, Inc., Morris Plains NJ Contract Employee for Pfizer, Memphis TN Fixed Asset Accountant

- Process fixed asset activity, reconciled various general ledger accounts, and research and resolve discrepancies to ensure accounting transactions are in compliance with Pfizer accounting policies and GAAP.
- Work collaboratively with Pfizer capital and finance leaders to ensure large scale capital projects are closed and recorded timely and accurately.
- Monitor fixed asset system functionality and perform maintenance as needed to ensure data integrity (Daily/Weekly/Monthly) impacted by external feeds and various purchasing system.
- Handle capital asset policy and procedure inquiries and ad hoc reporting requests.
- Research and resolve discrepancies and technical accounting questions; Assist FA
   Supervisor as needed; participate in or lead special projects that require creative and
   analytical skills.

August 28, 2005 – April 15, 2010

Askew Hargraves Harcourt & Associates, Inc., Lakeland, TN Full Charge Bookkeeper (Engineering Firm)

2009 Pinnacle Award recipient for Internal Client Relations 2007 Pinnacle Award recipient for Project/Systems

Presented in part for my participation in the company's accounting software conversion.

- Supervised a two person accounting office.
- Prepared and paid semimonthly payroll including all related federal tax deposits.
- Resolved issues relating to employee benefits (i.e. 401K, FSA, LTD/STD, medical, dental, etc.) relating to payroll deductions.
- Facilitated Federal and State corporate income tax returns with external preparer.
- Reconciled General Ledger for accurate financial reporting information.
- Reviewed and paid monthly accounts payable vendor invoices.
- Prepared monthly client billing and a corresponding sales report organizing income by department.
- Posted daily cash receipts to accounts receivable ledger.
- Collected outstanding balances on accounts receivable with weekly collection calls.
- Reviewed client contracts to assure accuracy of information in accounting software.
- Prepared, reviewed and analyzed monthly bank reconciliations.
- Served as bank administrator and primary liaison.

## September 2004 - June 2005

### WG Yates Construction, Biloxi, MS

### **Accounting/Billing Clerk**

- Prepared payment applications for the Biloxi division using accounting software.
- Trained new accounting staff in billing procedures.
- Used Construction Management forms (G702/G703).

## October 2000 – July 2003

### Urbitran Associates, Inc., New York, NY

#### Staff Accountant/Billing Supervisor (Engineering Firm)

- Supervised and maintained the day-to-day activities of a five person-billing department.
- Worked in conjunction with Project Managers to maintain the fluidity of current billing and helped reconcile past billing discrepancies.
- Reviewed client contracts and subcontractor contracts for accuracy and accounting information and set up new client accounts in accounting software.
- Prepared engineering and architectural billing for state, city, and private clients as well as maintained J/V accounts.
- Maintained a monthly report that contained detailed accounting information used in biweekly staff meetings. I reconciled monthly billing information i.e. sales journal, WIP, and A/R accounts as well as overseeing daily cash receipts transactions.
- Prepared financial billing information for biweekly Project Manager meetings.

## **Education:**

2008-2010 Strayer University, Memphis, TN

Master of Science, Major in Accounting

Concentration in Controllership - GPA 3.67

1991-1996

University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI **Bachelor of Arts**, Major in English

#### **Computer Skills:**

Accounting Programs:

- SAP/Computron
- Deltek Advantage CFMS 3.0
- Deltek Sema4

- Axium Ajera Portfolio
- Viewpoint
- Quickbooks